Mss.B.P274 Mss.B.P274
American Philosophical Society
- Series One: Papers
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, Sept. 20, 1811; 10 x 8-1/2; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
    Washington, Mississippi Territory, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Duplicate. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Patterson, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1811; 10x8; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
  - Letter to Robert [Maskell] Patterson, London, March 12, 1812; 9x7-1/2; Ronaldson, James, 1768-1842
    Leith, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Current events. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, March 20, 1812; 10x8-1/2; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
  - Letter to [Robert Maskell Patterson?], April 24, 1812; 8x6-1/2; Ronaldson, James, 1768-1842
    London, L. 2p. Extract. (see Patterson Papers.) Concerning American manufactures. This extract is written in a strange abbreviated from of English: no vowels are used.
  - Commencement address at the University of Pennsylvania, 1813; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    A.D. 9p. (see Patterson papers.) Refers to Franklin.
  - Will, March 13, 1813; 12-1/2x8; Bias, Ann, d. 1815
    A.D.S.: Ann Bias, James H. Ewing and Emma P. Fisher. 1p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Leaves estate to Mrs. Ann [Amy] Patterson.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, June 28, 1813; 12-1/2x8; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Patterson papers.) Is in love. News of the war. Refers to Perry.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1813; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L.S. 4p.,add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning the war.
  - Letter to Robert [Maskell] Patterson, Oct. 25, 1813; 10x8; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L. 3p.and end. Mutilated. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning the war. Describes Harrison and Perry. Death of Tecumseh.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Aug. 7, 9, 1813; 13x8; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L.S. 2p.,add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. War news.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, Jan. 8, 1814; 9-1/2x8; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
    Washington, Mississippi Territory, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. (see Patterson papers.) Asks a favor.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Feb. 10, 1814; 10x7-1/2; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. War news.
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Patterson, Philadelphia, May 12, 1814; 9-1/2x8; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Patterson, Philadelphia, Oct. 7, 1814; 10x7-1/2; Freeman, Thomas, d. 1821
    Washington, Mississippi Territory. A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning the war. Refers to Jackson.
  - Letter to Robert [Maskell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Jan. 24, 1815; 10x8; Leech, Richard F.
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Ask a favor.
  - List of mathematical instruments and books destined for the U.S.Coast and Geodetic Survey, deposited with Robert Patterson, Nov., 1815; 16x10-1/4; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    A.D.S. 7p.and end. (see Patterson papers)
  - Lecture on chemistry delivered to the Philadelphia medical society, Feb. 25, 1815; 12-1/2x7-1/2 and 8x5, 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [read] A.D. 11p. Incomplete. and (see Patterson Papers.) ----Draft of document. 8p.and end.: "R.M.P."
  - Receipt to Rob[er]t Patterson for a coffin for Mrs. Ann Bias, Nov. 16, 1815; 3-1/2x6; Lesley, Peter, Sr.
    D.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Receipt to Rob[er]t Patterson for burial fee of Ann Bias, Nov. 20, 1815; 3-1/2x4; Stuart, James
  - Receipt to Robert Patterson for use of hearse in burial of Ann Bias, Nov. 27, 1815; 2x4; Bacon, Samuel
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Letter to ----, March, 1816; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Draft of A.L. 2p. (see Patterson Papers.) Wishes changes made in the curriculum of the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, March 12, 1816; 10x8; Nulty, O. Eugenius, -1871.
    Carlisle, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Concerning change in the University of Pennsylvania. Mathematical problems.
  - Letter to the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, 1816?; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.] Draft of A.L. 2p. (see Patterson Papers.) Asks for permission to lecture on natural philosophy in the evenings and an assistant to help him.
  - List of students in class of natural philosophy, University of Pennsylvania, 1816-1817; 1817-1818; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.[containing label of David Hogan] in gray wrapper, consisting of 13 leaves. (see Patterson papers.)
  - List of books and instruments deposited with Robert Patterson for the coastal survey, Feb. 8, 1817; 13-1/2x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Pasted on this document is: Adams, D.P. Receipt to Robert Patterson; April 21, 1817.
  - Receipt to Robert Patterson of books and instruments for the coast survey, Feb. 8, 1817; 13-1/2x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 3p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Receipt to Robert Patterson for astronomical instruments, April 21, 1817; 5x8; Adams, David P.
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Pasted on document, see: Hassler, F.R. List of books...; Feb. 8, 1817.
  - Receipt to Mrs. Robert Patterson for donation to Princeton university from Ann Bias, May 16, 1817; 4-1/2x6-1/2; Snowden, Isaac
  - Lecture on atomic theory, read to the Philadelphia Medical Society, Feb. 28, 1818; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 10p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Letter to John Sergeant, Dec. 11, 1818; 6-1/2x4; American Philosophical Society
    Philosophical Hall, Draft of A.L.S.with initials: R.M.P[atterson]. 2p. (see Patterson Papers.) Asks aid to get loan of government instruments for astronomical observations.
  - Directions for finding variations in the magnetic needle, for the western expedition, 1818?; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    [ca.]. A.D.S. 3p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Note to Robert Patterson, May 7, 1819; 4x8; Babcock, S
    New Castle, A.N.S. 1p.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Asks for a barometer.
  - Suggestions for the expedition on meteorological observations, 1819; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    topography, traverse distances, knowledge of the Indians in astronomy, etc.; [ca.]. A.D. 4p.,end.: "A.P.S." (see Patterson Papers.) For Major Long's expedition?
  - Some remarks concerning astronomical observations for the western expedition, 1819?; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    [ca.] A.D.S. 4p.,end.: "A.P.S." (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Lecture on vision, March 29, [18]20; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 3p. (see Patterson Papers)
  - Letter to Robert [Maskell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Nov. 13, 1820; 8x6; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, Dec. 5, 1820; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, Draft of A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Requests new natural philosophy instruments.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, March 2, 1821; 10x8; Stansbury, Daniel
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. (see Patterson papers.) Concerning nautical astronomy.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, March 5, 1821; 10x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Cape Vincent, A.L.S. 5p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. Wishes him to sell his library and instruments. Refers to J.Vaughan.
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, Sept. 4, 1821; 13x8; Reid, Robert C.
    Erie, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Robert [Maskell] Patterson, Philadelphia, April 18, 1822; 10x8; Slaughter, Daniel F.
    Springfield, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Asks for information about the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Notes on the number of prizes in the lottery being held for building a canal, 1822; 6-1/2x4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.] A.D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) On same sheet as: P. Canfield...Has the pleasure...; Jan. 1. 1822.
  - Mathematical scraps, consisting of calculations on various subjects, 1822; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D.S.with initials. 1vol.with paper cover [containing label of David Hogan], consisting of 21 leaves of which 19 contain writing,plus 1 leaf inserted. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Letter to Robert M[askell] Patterson, University, July 24, 1825; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Reid, Robert C.
  - List of Robert Patterson's apparatus for natural philosophy, 1825?; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.]. A.D. 8p. (see Patterson Papers.) Refers to a Franklin electrical instrument.
  - Letter to Robert Maskell Patterson, Aug. 4, 1826
    A.L.S. 1 p.
  - Concerning annuities and insurance, 1826; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.]. A.D. 4p.and end.: "Notes on Annuities. Death of Adams & Jefferson." (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Concerning the deaths of Jefferson and Adams, [1826?]; 8x6 and 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 5p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Mathematical chances of their dying on the same day.
  - Bill of lading of materials shipped to Bernard Peyton, Aug. 21, 1828; 5-3/4x10-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, Printed D.filled in in ms. 1p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Enclosed originally in letter from R.M. Patterson to B.Peyton; Aug. 29, 1828.
  - Letter to Bernard Peyton, Aug. 29, 1828; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and end. Enc. Draft (see Patterson paper Sends instructions for forwarding items to the University of Virginia for him. For enclosure, see: R.M.Patterson. Bill of lading...; Aug. 21, 1828.
  - Receipt for boxes sent to the University of Virginia for R. M. Patterson, Sept. 17, 1828; 4-3/4x7-1/2; Peyton, Bernard, 1792-1854
    Richmond, D. 1p.and add.,end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Resolution that [R. M.] Patterson may use his philosophical apparatus, and that Mr. Jefferson's donation be removed from its present location, Oct. 4, 1828; 10x7-1/2; University of Virginia. Visitors
    A.D.S.: N. P. Trist. 2p.and add.,end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Letter to [Robert M.] Patterson, University of Virginia, Oct. 18, 1828; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peyton, Bernard, 1792-1854
    Richmond, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Patterson papers.) Modes of shipping instruments and furniture to him, at the University of Virginia.
  - Resolution that [Robert M. Patterson] may have a person purchase tools and repair "the instruments in the Philosophical and Astronomical" rooms of the University, [1828?]; 5-1/2x7-3/4; University of Virginia
    A.D.S.: H. G. Davis. 1p.and end.by R. M.Patterson. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Accounts at the University of Virginia, Sept. 10-Feb. 23, 1828-[1833]; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 6p.of assorted sizes and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1828-1829; 7x3; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 15p., some of which are in pencil. (see Patterson papers.) Contains references to William Strickland and Dunglison. Expenses from Philadelphia to the University of Virginia.
  - Account with the proctor of students in natural philosophy at the University of Virginia, 1828-1835; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 7p.of various sizes and end. (see Patterson Papers.) Payment for teaching.
  - Estimate for transporting apparatus to the University of Virginia for the teaching of Natural Philosophy, Nov., 1829; 10x7-3/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p.,on address leaf. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Receipt to [Robert Maskell] Patterson for tools and travelling expenses to repair instruments for the University of Virginia, Sept. 4, 1829; 4-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    A.D.S. 1p.and end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Statement of accounts to Robert M. Patterson, Sept. 18, 1829; 7-3/4x8; Peyton, Bernard, 1792-1854
    D. 1p.and end.and wrapper. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Letter to [Robert Maskell] Patterson, Sept. 22, 1829; 10x8; Peyton, Bernard, 1792-1854
    Richmond, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Patterson papers.) Business. Refers to instruments sent to the University of Virginia.
  - Examinations in Natural Philosophy, July 14, 1829-1834; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1vol.with decorative cover, consisting of 20 leaves,of which 12 contain writing, plus 5 leaves inserted in the volume. 7-1/2x6-1/4. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Questions proposed for graduation in Natural Philosophy, May 18, 1832; 8x6-1/4; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 5p.and end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Concerning gravity and problems involving gravity, Sept. 22, 1832; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 9p. (see Patterson Papers.) Mathematics.
  - Under authority of resolutions...addressed to Robert Maskell Patterson, Dec. 6, 1832; Girard College.
  - Letter to the trustees of Girard college, Jan. 14, 1833; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [sent] Draft of A.L. 7p.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Proposes plan for the college.
  - Letter to R[obert] M[askell] Patterson, University of Virginia, Jan. 19, 1833; 10x8; McIlvaine, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. (see Patterson Papers.) Forwards copy of Girard's will and information concerning the founding of the college
  - Mathematical problem by Edward Sang, 1833; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.] A.D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Extracted from the Edinburgh new philosophical journal, Jan-April, 1833, p.311.
  - Barometrical measurements, Nov.-May 3, 1833-1834; 15x7-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Barometric hyposometry?
  - Poem to G. B., May 7, 1834; 10x8; T., G.
    D. 1p. (see Patterson papers.) On the reverse is mathematical problem..
  - Observations on the solar eclipse, Nov. 30, 1834; 13x8 and 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 4p.,end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Examination in mathematics for the University of Virginia, Dec. 10, 1834; 8x6-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 2p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Recitation roll of the senior class in natural philosophy at the University of Virginia, 1834; 13x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    D. 7p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Lecture rolls in natural philosophy at the University of Virginia, 1834-1835; 13x8 and 11x9; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
  - Oral examination on heat, electricity and magnetism, May 1, 1835; 12-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 1p.and end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Lecture (?) on physical astronomy as farewell lecture at the University of Virginia, June 18, 1835; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.D. 8p. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Letter to the University of Virginia, 1835; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.] Draft of A.L. 2p. (see Patterson Papers.) Offers to sell apparatus for course in natural philosophy.
  - Observations of the solar eclipse of May 15, 1836, May, 1836; 10x8; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.]. D. 1p. (see Patterson Papers)
  - Letter to A[lexander] D[allas] Bache, Philadelphia, May 15, 1836; 10x8-1/2; Gummer, John, 1784-1847
    Haverford, L.S. John Gummer and J.Vaughan. 1p. and add.,end. (see Patterson Papers.) Observation of the solar eclipse.
  - Eclipse of the sun at Philosophical Hall, May 15, 1836; 15x9; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia, A.D. 1p.and end. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Note to [Robert Maskell] Patterson, May, 1836?; 4-1/2x9; Riggs, W. H. C.
    []. A.N.S. In pencil. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Wishes him to take a transit of the sun. Refers to Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 5, 1836; 10x8; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Friendly letter. Forwards data of the solar eclipse.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], June 20, 1836; 10x8; Wilson, Henry, 1812-1875
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Sends information concerning the solar eclipse.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 28, 1836; 9x7-1/2; Ferguson, J. F. I.
    Elizabethtown, A.L.S. 4p.,end.: "A.P.S...." (see Patterson Papers.) Sends date concerning the solar eclipse Cf. Minutes, p.688.
  - Note to [Alexander Dallas] Bache, June, 1836; 3-1/2x8; Walker, Sears Cook, 1805-1853
    [ca.]. A.N. 1p.and add. (see Patterson Papers.) Corrects Henry Wilson's figures of the solar eclipse.
  - Letter to R[obert] Patterson, Philadelphia, Nov. 24, 1840; 10x8, and 12-1/2x8; C., S. F.
    University of Virginia, A.L.S.with initials. 6p.,add.: "Care of Dr. R.M. Patterson..." and (see Patterson Papers.) Concerning the death of Prof. Davis.
  - Letter to [Franklin] Pierce, March, 1853; 10x8; Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864
    [ca.]. L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Concerning the sale of Godon's cabinet, 1840?; 8x5; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    [ca.] A.D. 1p. Incomplete. (see Patterson Papers.) On same sheet are mathematical and astronomical problems.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, Philadelphia, Oct. 6, 1845; 9x7-1/2; American Agricultural Association
    New York, A.L.S.: And. H. Green. 1p.and add., end. (see Patterson Papers.) Informs him of his election as councellor.
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], Feb. 28, 1853; 10x8; Martin, George H.
    Philadelphia, (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint. Refers to R.M.Patterson
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce;], March, 1853; 10x8; Edmonds, Francis William, 1806-1863
    ca. L.S.: F. W. Edmonds and 11 others. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March, 1853; 10x8; Leiper, Samuel M.
    [ca.]. L. 1p. Copy. Enc. (see Patterson Papers.) Concerning Robert Patterson as director of the mint, on the testimonial of Eckert. For enclosure, see: G.N.Eckert to S. M.Leiper; March 8, 1853.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March, 1853; 10x8; Robinson, C. M.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint. Refers to R. M. Patterson.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Whelen, E. S.
    [ca.]. L.S.by E.S.Whelen and 10 others. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to [Franklin] Pierce, March 1, 1853; 10x8; Campbell, Hugh
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March 4, 1853; 10x8; Elliott, Isaac
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint. Refers to R.M.Patterson.
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], March 4, 1853; 10X8; Leiper, George Gray, 1786-1868
    Leiperville, A.L.S. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint. Refers to Robert Patterson, Robert M. Patterson, the APS, Thomas Jefferson, and Andrew Jackson.
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], March 4, 1853; 10x8; University of Pennsylvania. School of Medicine
    Philadelphia, L.S.: William Gibson and 6 others. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], March 5, 1853; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: F. Fraley, Franklin Bache, and 22 others. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l M.Leiper, Philadelphia, March 8, 1853; 10x8; Eckert, G. N. (George N.)
    L. 2p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Thinks Robert Patterson should be director of the mint. Enclosed originally in letter from S.M. Leiper to F. Pierce; [ca.March 1853.].
  - Letter to George N. Eckert, Philadelphia, March 8, 1853; 10x8; Leiper, Samuel M.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Asks his opinion of Robert Patterson as director of the mint. For reply, see: Eckert to S.M.Leiper; March 8, 1853.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March 8, 1853; 10x8; Van Nest, Abraham, 1777-1864
    New York, L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to Pierce Butler, Washington, March 9, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Adams & Co.
    Philadelphia, L. 2p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Hopes he will aid in getting Robert Patterson the post as director of the mint
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], March 9, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Borie, A. E. (Adolph Edward), 1809-1880
    Philadelphia, L.S.: A. E. Borie and 3 others. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson papers) Recommends Robert Patterson for director of the mint.
  - Letter to W[illiam] I. Leiper, March 9, 1853; 10x8; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    L. 1p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Hopes Robert Patterson gets the post of director of the mint.
  - Letter to [Franklin Pierce], March 10, 1853; 10 x 8; Read, John M. (John Meredith), 1797-1874
    Philadelphia, L. 1 p. Copy. (see Patterson Papers). Recommends Robert Patterson for director of the mint.
  - Letter to Franklin Pierce, March 11, 1853; 10x8; Gilpin, Henry D. (Henry Dilworth), 1801-1860
  - Letter to F[ranklin] Pierce, March 11, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Yost, J. S.
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. copy. (see Patterson Papers.) Recommends Robert Patterson as director of the mint.
  - Letter to Mrs. Helen N. Patterson, March 12, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Grier, Robert Cooper, 1794-1870
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Thinks Robert Patterson is the best man for the directorship of the mint.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Helen N.] Patterson, Sept. 13, 1854; 10x8; Tutwiler, Henry, 1807-1884
    Wadesboro, N.C., L. Copy(?). 3p. (see Patterson Papers.) Sympathy for the death of R.M.Patterson. Refers to the APS.
  - Codicil to will, May 16, 1863; 6-1/2x4; Nevins, Elizabeth West
    Copy of D. 1p. In pencil. (see Patterson Papers.) See next to last page in [R.Patterson] Hints...: [ca.1793]. Not found April, 2011.
  - Letters to Thomas Leiper Patterson, 1892-1905; 11x8-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819-1909
    Typed D. 2p. Extracts. (see Patterson papers.) Concerning C.W. Peale, etc. From originals in possession of Mrs.A.Waldo Jones, Still House Road, Vinings,Ga. Oct.1963.
  - Note to go with "Hints..." by Robert Patterson, July 8, 1937; 5-1/2x4; Patterson, Mary R.
    Typed N.S. 1p. (see Patterson Papers.) Pasted in front cover of: [R.Patterson] Hints...; [ca.1793]. Not found April, 2011.
  - Prescription., Undated; 7x4-1/2; Berger, Jean Francois, 1779-1833
    D. 1p.and end. In French. (see Patterson Papers.)
  - Certificate concerning Leiper's canal, Undated; 6-1/2x4; Francis, Tench, 1730-1800
    [ca.1792]. A.D.S. - 1p.and end. (see Patterson papers.)
  - Examination in the school of "antient" languages, Undated